KOEN COLPAERT RESUME

Project Manager and Data Scientist

Status: Diensthoofd Bedrijfsdata en Informatie, Vlaamse Overheid

Fields: Business Intelligence, Data Warehousing, Data Science, Project Management

Prefers: MSSQL, R, Git, IBM Cognos

Activities: Photographer, Urban Explorer, Vinyl Collector

Wetteren, België www.colpaert.org koen@colpaert.org +32 487 02 44 95

Summary

Digital media graduate with project experience in the field of technology based assessment. Currently working as IT Consultant at We4IT, Bremen in the field of IBM Notes Domino and XPages applications. Master studies focused on teams from different disciplines and cultural backgrounds on solutions for complex problems.

Experience

IT Consultant for IBM XPages and Notes Domino - We4IT GmbH Bremen 2014 - Present · Realize projects in XPages and We4IT Aveedo, monitor project status, conduct reports · Implement the frontend for a BPMN compatible engine within We4IT Aveedo Poster Presentation - DELFI Conference 2013 / 09 · Co-published poster with paper on usability guidelines for tests with functional illiterates · Presented results to conference audience at conference event Scientific Employee / Software Development - University of Bremen 2012 - 2014 · Invented a flexible assessment framework, targeting industrial trainees · Supervised software development lifecycle, Recruited team members **Project Management Simulation Training** - Getoq Consulting 2011 / 11 · Performed a two-day project simulation from management perspective · Topics included customer contracts, change management, controlling, operational tasks 2010 - 2011 Student Assistant / Programmer - otulea.uni-bremen.de · Realized an online diagnosis platform for workforce literacy development (Flex) · Modeled software design, implemented various prototypes, conducted usability tests

Education	
Graduated as M.Sc. Political and Social Sciences - University of Ghent	1989 / 94
Master Thesis: De informatiemaatschappij: een literatuurstudie	
Postgraduate - University of Brussels	1994 - 1995
Master Thesis: De West-Europese Unie na Maastricht	
Master Studies Digital Media - University of Bremen	2012 - 2015
Inter-cultural classes in English, covering special topics in computer science and design Professionalized in research methods, software development and e-assessment	
Semester Abroad - University of Melbourne	2009 - 2010

- · Mastered six months of study and trans-cultural experience in Melbourne, Australia
- · Finished machine programming, information visualization, professional essay writing